=The Rise of Zhao Jiadi=
=صعود تشاو جيا دي=
(Adapted from "Out of His League" by Fenghuo Xizhuhou)
(مقتبس من "خارج مستواه" بقلم فنغهوو شيجوهوي)
=Episode 10=
=الحلقة 10=
(Zhao Jiadi, I'll say it again.)
(تشاو جيا دي، سأقولها مرة أخرى.)
(Without me, you're nothing.)
(بدوني، أنت لا شيء.)
Only ten days left.
بقي عشرة أيام فقط.
It's not too late to regret it.
لم يفت الأوان على الندم.
I can up the stakes.
يمكنني رفع الرهان.
Fine. Ten million after graduation.
حسنًا. عشرة ملايين بعد التخرج.
As long as you make it, I'll do what you say.
طالما أنك تنجح، سأفعل ما تطلبه.
I already said it.
لقد قلت ذلك بالفعل.
Once I make it, you apologize to my mom.
عندما أنجح، تعتذر لأمي.
As for who I am,
أما بالنسبة لمن أكون،
I'll figure that out
سأكتشف ذلك
before graduation.
قبل التخرج.
Interesting.
مثير للاهتمام.
We meet again.
نلتقي مجددًا.
The business Empress, Qi Dongcao.
إمبراطورة الأعمال، تشي دونغتساو.
You really live up to the name.
أنتِ حقًا تستحقين هذا اللقب.
Smart and beautiful.
ذكية وجميلة.
A girl like her working under some thug
فتاة مثلها تعمل تحت إمرة أحد البلطجية
at Jinhai Group?
في مجموعة جينهاي؟
What a waste.
يا له من إهدار.
Showing up uninvited
الظهور دون دعوة
is typical of your generation.
هذا أمر معتاد من جيلكم.
Chen Hongxiong,
تشن هونغ شيونغ،
you might as well change your name to Chen Hoaxer.
من الأفضل أن تغير اسمك إلى "تشن المخادع".
You stalked me all the way to a noodle stall.
تتبعتني حتى كشك النودلز.
I'm here for Zhao Jiadi.
أنا هنا من أجل تشاو جيا دي.
I heard you and your dad
سمعت أنك ووالدك
are playing some very interesting game.
تلعبان لعبة مثيرة جداً.
I'm intrigued.
لقد أثار ذلك اهتمامي.
Zhao Jiadi,
تشاو جيا دي،
need a hand?
تحتاج إلى مساعدة؟
From you?
منك أنت؟
Why?
لماذا؟
When you spend money, it's to have fun, right?
عندما تنفق المال، يكون ذلك للمتعة، أليس كذلك؟
If I can make that nouveau riche bumpkin eat dirt,
إذا استطعت أن أجعل ذلك الثري الجديد يتلقى الهزيمة،
it'd be enough to keep me happy for days.
سيكفيني ذلك لأكون سعيداً لأيام.
So how do you plan to help?
إذاً كيف تخطط للمساعدة؟
If you can best me, then I'll help you.
إذا استطعت أن تهزمني، سأساعدك.
I'm really starting to take an interest in you.
بدأت فعلاً أهتم بك.
But the loser has to pay the price.
لكن الخاسر عليه أن يدفع الثمن.
What do you have to offer?
ماذا ستقدم؟
A stake in the milk tea shop.
حصة في محل شاي الحليب.
How much?
كم النسبة؟
Let's say...
لنقل...
twenty percent.
عشرون بالمئة.
I thought you'd go all in.
ظننت أنك ستراهن بكل شيء.
No need to go big.
لا داعي للمبالغة.
Just enough is enough.
القدر الكافي يكفي.
What are we playing? You pick.
ما هي لعبتنا؟ اختر أنت.
You decide.
الأمر لك.
What?
ماذا؟
Certainly.
بكل تأكيد.
You pick.
اختر أنت.
Interesting. I like it.
مثير للاهتمام. أعجبني.
Alright, let's get this game started!
حسنًا، لنبدأ هذه اللعبة!
Boss.
رئيس.
Garlic, please.
ثوم، من فضلك.
Coming!
قادِم!
You two want a game, huh?
أنتم الاثنان تريدان اللعب، أليس كذلك؟
Alright.
حسنًا.
Let's go. Peel garlic, bet odd or even.
هيا بنا. قشّروا الثوم، واراهنوا على فردي أو زوجي.
Pick one.
اختر واحدًا.
Age before wisdom. You go first.
الكِبر قبل الحكمة. أنت تبدأ أولاً.
Zhao Jiadi.
تشاو جيا دي.
"Jiadi" as in top of the imperial exam list.
"جيا دي" تعني الأول في قائمة امتحان الإمبراطورية.
It means best of the best.
يعني الأفضل بين الجميع.
And "one" is an odd number.
و"واحد" هو رقم فردي.
So, you believe in destiny.
إذًا، أنت تؤمن بالقدر.
Which means you can only pick even.
وهذا يعني أنه يمكنك اختيار الأرقام الزوجية فقط.
That's fine.
لا بأس بذلك.
I believe in destiny too.
أنا أيضًا أؤمن بالقدر.
Alright then.
حسنًا إذًا.
Let's play your little game.
لنلعب لعبتك الصغيرة.
Odd.
فردي.
Even.
زوجي.
Looks like destiny's still on my side.
يبدو أن القدر لا يزال في صفي.
Draft a share transfer agreement now.
قم بإعداد اتفاقية نقل الأسهم الآن.
Make it out to Tran Organization.
اجعلها باسم منظمة تران.
Yeah, do it immediately.
نعم، افعل ذلك فوراً.
Boss, the contract will be signed tomorrow.
سيدي، سيتم توقيع العقد غداً.
Kid, you're a pretty decent gambler.
يا فتى، أنت مقامر لا بأس به.
Way more interesting than your old man.
أكثر إثارة للاهتمام من والدك بكثير.
I didn't get to see that bumpkin eat dirt,
لم أتمكن من رؤية ذلك الريفي وهو يُهزم،
but I did get to see something even more fun.
لكنني رأيت شيئًا أكثر متعة.
See you around.
أراك لاحقًا.
Most expensive garlic in all of Haicheng.
أغلى ثوم في كل هايتشنغ.
Won't you try some first?
ألا تجرب بعضه أولاً؟
Garlic's not my thing.
الثوم ليس من الأشياء التي أحبها.
Coffee suits me better.
القهوة تناسبني أكثر.
My new secretary's really good at this.
سكرتيرتي الجديدة بارعة حقًا في هذا.
You're always welcome to drop by for coffee.
أنت مرحب بك دائمًا لزيارتنا من أجل القهوة.
I'll be waiting.
سأكون في الانتظار.
This kid is kind of interesting.
هذا الفتى مثير للاهتمام نوعًا ما.
That guy is a fool.
ذلك الرجل أحمق.
Boss, even if you refused to pay
يا رئيس، حتى لو رفضت أن تدفع
after losing the game,
بعد أن خسرت اللعبة،
what could he do about it?
ماذا كان يمكنه أن يفعل حيال ذلك؟
So you're saying
إذًا أنت تقول
I bested a fool?
أنني هزمت أحمقًا؟
That's not what I meant.
هذا ليس ما قصدته.
Then are you saying
إذًا هل تقول
I misread the situation?
أنني أسأت فهم الموقف؟
That I didn't consider the consequences of losing?
أنني لم أضع في اعتباري عواقب الخسارة؟
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I misspoke.
لقد أخطأت في التعبير.
Or do you think
أم أنك تعتقد
my word
أن كلمتي
is not even worth two million?
لا تساوي حتى مليونين؟
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Please forgive me.
أرجوك سامحني.
A beautiful coffee cup
فنجان قهوة جميل
makes me hesitate to smash it.
يجعلني أتردد في كسره.
So,
لذا،
you'd better learn when to keep quiet.
من الأفضل أن تتعلم متى تصمت.
Not everyone at the table
ليس كل من يجلس على الطاولة
deserves to play the game.
يستحق أن يلعب اللعبة.
But I'm already at the table.
لكنني بالفعل على الطاولة.
And I'm not leaving.
ولن أغادر.